Adrián López Calvo

Software Developer

Calle del Poeta Joan Maragall 13, 28020, Madrid, Madrid Spain

☑ adrian.lc.work@gmail.com ☐ +34 676 789 447
in adrianlc ☐ AdrianLC ☑ AdrianLC ☑ AdrianLC

Experience mostly on *backend* web development and *Python's* ecosystem with a preference for open source tools. Things I love to work with include: APIs, testing, continuous integration, databases, performance tuning, *i18n* and more yet to discover!

SKILLS

Programming

Advanced

python | java | php | javascript | c |
git | testing

Backend

Advanced

django | celery | sql | postgresql | mysql | mongodb | elasticsearch | web services | scrapping

DevOps

Intermediate

ansible | docker | kubernetes | vagrant | continuous integration | amazon web services | google cloud | travis

Frontend

Beginner

html | django & jinja templates | css | angularjs | jquery

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer at HundredRooms

June 2016 - September 2017

http://hundredrooms.com

Skills acquired: python | celery | scrapy | asyncio | mysql | mongodb | ansible | docker | kubernetes | gce | grafana

Worked on getting the data processing core of the product to the next level.

- Migrated a big part of the systems from in-house servers to the cloud with Ansible.
- Moved most of them to Docker and a Kubernetes cluster.
- Established a reliable deployment process and adequate testing tools.
- Implemented real time data synchronization between MongoDB and MySQL.
- Integrated external data into the platform through several APIs and scraping.
- Developed asynchronous components of the system with Asyncio.
- Upgraded a huge part of the code base from Python 2 to 3.
- Worked on improving the database schema.

Software Engineer at Smartvel

October 2014 - June 2016

http://smartvel.com

Skills acquired: python | django | django-rest-framework | celery | postgresql | postgis | redis | mongodb | elasticsearch | ansible | vagrant | aws

Built products of the company focusing mostly on backend and web development.

- Migrated the processing core to an asynchronous queue system with Celery.
- Managed the work queues: routing, priorities, monitoring, concurrency, autoscaling, deployments.
- Built a component to translate texts, obtained through scrapping, automatically.
- Implemented several tools to improve names and boundaries in the geographic data.
- Maintained geographic boundaries with QGIS and shapefiles.
- Set up the MongoDB server with Ansible.
- Handled several major upgrades such as: MongoDB 2 to 3, Django 1.7 to 1.9 or Rest Framework 2 to 3.
- Optimized critical SQL queries, including Postgresql extensions such as postgis, trigrams and full text search.

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science at Universidade de Santiago de Compostela 2009 - 2013

Major courses: oo programming | data structures & algorithms | software engineering | operative systems | networks | system administration | web development | web services | distributed computing

LANGUAGES

Spanish native speaker

English advanced

Galician native speaker

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

